<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta - Smarter Search</title>
    <link>https://meta.sc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Meta - Smarter Search</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Meta</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:52:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meta.sc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta - Terms of Service</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:52:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Meta Terms of Service&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Thank you for choosing Meta&amp;trade;, the single portal to all of your files. Meta provides an easy-to-use access point allowing you to locate all of your content,
    whether it&#39;s available locally or on the cloud. We think you&#39;ll enjoy our platform, which is governed by the following Terms of Service (&amp;quot;Agreement&amp;quot;).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Rastech Software, Inc. (&amp;quot;Rastech Software,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;us&amp;quot;) provides and operates the Meta services though our downloadable applications (the &amp;quot;Meta Apps&amp;quot;)
    and the Meta website (the &amp;quot;Meta Website&amp;quot;), which may be modified from time to time in our sole discretion (collectively, the &amp;quot;Services&amp;quot;). By registering
    with us, or by using the Services, you agree to be bound by this Agreement, which we may change at any time by posting a notice on the Meta Website and/or
    the Meta Apps. Your continued use of the Services constitutes your consent to such changes. PLEASE READ THIS AGREEMENT CAREFULLY AND CHECK THESE TERMS OF
    USE PERIODICALLY FOR CHANGES. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS OF USE, YOU MAY NOT USE THE SERVICES.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;1. Conditions on Using the Services&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    a) &lt;strong&gt;Basic Terms. &lt;/strong&gt; We may, in our sole discretion, refuse to offer the Services to any person or entity. We may, without notice and in our
    sole discretion, terminate your right to use the Services, or any portion of thereof, and block or prevent your future access to and use of the Services or
    any portion thereof.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    b) &lt;strong&gt;Your Account. &lt;/strong&gt;A Meta account is required in order to use the Services. You agree to provide only accurate and true information in
    connection with the creation of your account, and to update your information as necessary so it remains accurate and current. You may not transfer your
    account to any third party. You are responsible for keeping your account login information confidential and for any and all activities that occur under
    your account. You agree to notify us immediately if you suspect or become aware of any unauthorized use of your account or other breach of security on the
    Services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    c) &lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy.&lt;/strong&gt; Our Privacy Policy, which describes how we may collect and use your information, may be viewed at www.meta.sc/privacy
    and is incorporated into and considered a part of this Agreement. By using the Services, you agree that your information may be collected and used in
    accordance with our Privacy Policy and this Agreement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    d) &lt;strong&gt;Minors. &lt;/strong&gt;THE SERVICES ARE NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN UNDER 13, and persons under the age of 13 are prohibited from registering with or
    using the Services. You represent and warrant that you are more than 18 years of age or, if you are above 13 and below 18 years of age, you are an
    emancipated minor, or possess legal parental or guardian consent, and are fully able and competent to abide by and comply with the terms, conditions,
    obligations, affirmations, representations, and warranties set forth in this Agreement. This provision is void where prohibited by law and the right to
    access the Sites and Services is revoked in such jurisdictions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    e) &lt;strong&gt;Paid Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;. If applicable, you may be accessing the Service by choosing and paying for one of the paid account plans available and
    detailed at meta.sc/pricing. You may cancel your Meta paid account at any time but you won&#39;t be issued a refund. Your paid account will remain in effect
    until it&#39;s cancelled or terminated under these Terms. If you don&#39;t pay for your Paid Account on time, we reserve the right to suspend it or reduce the
    Service levels accessible to you accordingly. We may change the fees in effect but will give you advance notice of these changes via a message to the email
    address associated with your account.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;2. Ownership and Content&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    a) &lt;strong&gt;Generally. &lt;/strong&gt;By using the Services, you will encounter &amp;quot;Meta Content,&amp;quot; which includes all of the images, text, information, data, audio,
    video, graphics and other material included on or otherwise made available through the Services, via either the Meta Apps or the Meta Website, excluding
    User Content. &amp;quot;User Content&amp;quot; which includes all of the files, file structures, and other data that you submit to us, or which we must access, in order to
    provide the Services to you. Except as otherwise set forth in this Agreement we do not claim ownership over any User Content, and each user is solely
    responsible for any User Content that they provide to us via the Services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    b) &lt;strong&gt;Ownership. &lt;/strong&gt;All Meta Content is owned by Rastech Software, Inc. or its licensors, and is protected by U.S. and international copyright
    laws, trademark laws and/or other proprietary rights and laws. As between you and Rastech Software, Inc. and its licensors, Rastech Software, Inc. or its
    licensors own and retain, solely and exclusively, all rights, title and interest in and to the Services, and all Meta Content that we or our licensors
    create and that we make available to you through the Services, including but not limited to any and all copyrights, trademark rights, trade secret rights,
    patent rights, database rights and other intellectual property and proprietary rights therein. META and all associated logos and the other trademarks,
    service marks, logos and trade names displayed on or in connection with the Services are the registered and unregistered trademarks and service marks of
    Rastech Software, Inc. or third parties in the United States and/or other countries. Your use of the Services does not grant you any ownership over any
    Meta Content, and except for the limited license we grant you under this Agreement, your use of the Services does not grant you any license or permission
    under any copyright, trademark or other intellectual property rights of Rastech Software, Inc. or any third party. We reserve all rights not expressly
    granted to you in this Agreement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;c) &lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Service and Content License. &lt;/strong&gt;
    We grant you a limited, non-exclusive, non-sublicensable and non-transferable license to use the Services as they are provided to you by us, only as set
    forth in this Agreement and in the manner described here. Except as expressly permitted in this Agreement, you may not reproduce, distribute, adapt,
    modify, translate, create derivative works from, publish or otherwise use any portion of the Services or Meta Content for any purpose without express prior
    written permission from us or the applicable rights holder. Any commercial exploitation of the Services or Meta Content without express prior written
    permission from us or the applicable rights holder is strictly prohibited.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    d) &lt;strong&gt;Software. &lt;/strong&gt;The Meta App, and all other software and software-as-a-service (SAAS) used in connection with the Services (&amp;quot;Software&amp;quot;) is
    proprietary to us or to third parties, and except as may be required to exercise the foregoing license grant, any use, redistribution, sale, decompilation,
    reverse engineering, disassembly, translation or reduction of such software to human-readable form is prohibited. You agree that we may update the Software
    without notice, at any time and in our sole discretion, and that this Agreement will apply to any updated versions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;3. User Content&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    a) &lt;strong&gt;Generally. &lt;/strong&gt; You are solely responsible for ensuring that any User Content you submit to the Services complies with any applicable laws
    and third party rights, including but not limited to any intellectual property rights, privacy rights and publicity rights. You agree that any information
    included in your User Content may be used in accordance with our Privacy Policy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    b) &lt;strong&gt;User Feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; We appreciate your feedback and suggestions about our Services, but you agree that any feedback or suggestions submitted
    to us about the Services are entirely voluntary and that we will be free to use any such feedback or suggestions as we see fit and without any obligation
    to you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    c) &lt;strong&gt;License to Rastech Software, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt; During the operation of the Services, we may access, scan, copy, modify, view metadata, and otherwise
    manipulate your User Content on a temporary basis solely to provide the Services as set forth under this Agreement. We do not claim any ownership rights in
    your User Content, and you remain the owner of any intellectual property rights that you have in your User Content. By using the Services, you grant
    Rastech Software, Inc. a worldwide, non-exclusive, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, sub-licensable (through multiple tiers) right and license to use,
    reproduce, adapt, modify, translate, and create derivative works from your User Content, solely for the purposes of developing, distributing, providing,
    and improving the Services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    d) &lt;strong&gt;User Representations. &lt;/strong&gt;By submitted User Content, you represent and warrant that (i) you own or otherwise control all of the rights to
    your User Content, (ii) the use of your User Content does not violate this Agreement or the law, and will not violate any rights of or cause injury to any
    person or entity, and (iii) your User Content will not violate the content restrictions set forth in &lt;strong&gt;Section 3(f)&lt;/strong&gt; of this Agreement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    e) &lt;strong&gt;Right to Monitor or Remove. &lt;/strong&gt; You agree that you, and bear all risks associated with, your User Content. Rastech Software, Inc. does not
    permanently store entire files on its servers. However, we do not permit the infringement of intellectual property rights on the Services, and will remove
    User Content from the Services if properly notified that such User Content infringes on another&#39;s intellectual property rights. We reserve the right to
    remove User Content from the Services, in whole or in part, without prior notice, for any reason or for no reason at all. Without limiting our right to
    terminate a user pursuant to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 9 &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;of this Agreement, we reserve the right to terminate the account of any user of the Services
    who has been notified of infringing activity more than twice and/or has had User Content removed from the Service more than twice. We also reserve the
    right to decide whether User Content is appropriate and complies with this Agreement for violations other than violations of intellectual property law. We
    may remove any User Content and/or terminate a user account for uploading such material in violation of this Agreement at any time, without prior notice
    and at our sole discretion.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    f) &lt;strong&gt;Restrictions.&lt;/strong&gt; You agree that you will not use the Services to:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    i. Promote any illegal activity, or advocate, promote or assist any unlawful act;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    ii. Violate the legal rights (including the rights of publicity and privacy) of others or contain any material that could give rise to any civil or
    criminal liability under applicable laws or regulations or that otherwise may be in conflict with this Agreement and our Privacy Policy;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    iii. Transmit any pornographic, obscene, offensive, threatening, harassing, libelous, hate-oriented, harmful, defamatory, racist, illegal, or otherwise
    objectionable material or content;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    iv. Transmit any material or content that attempts to falsely state or otherwise misrepresent your identity or affiliation with a person or entity;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    v. Transmit material or content that promotes, provides, or relates to instructional information about illegal activities or promotes physical harm or
    injury against any individual or group;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    vi. Transmit or otherwise make available any unsolicited or unauthorized advertising, promotional materials, &amp;quot;junk mail,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;spam,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;chain letters,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;pyramid
    schemes,&amp;quot; or any other form of solicitation;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    vii. Transmit or encourage the transmission of any material that may infringe the intellectual property rights or other rights of third parties, including
    trademark, copyright, or right of publicity; and
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    viii. Transmit any nude or sexually suggestive photos.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;4. Other Websites and Services&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The Services may contain links and features that enable you to access other third-party websites or services that are not owned or controlled by us. We do
    not control these websites or services, and we are not responsible for the contents of any linked site. A link does not imply endorsement of, sponsorship
    of, or affiliation with the linked site by Rastech Software, Inc. Please exercise caution before proceeding to any third-party website or entering into any
    transaction with third parties linked to from the Services. Our Services contain features that permit you to interact with various services provided by
    third parties, including Dropbox, Google, Evernote, and OneDrive. By using these features, you agree to abide by the Terms of Services that apply to each
    third-party service. The owners of these other services do not sponsor or endorse our Services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;5. Warranty Disclaimers, Limitations of Liability, Indemnity&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES.&lt;/strong&gt;
    Rastech Software, Inc. makes no representations or warranties of any kind regarding the Services or the Meta Content. YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF
    THE SERVICES IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK. THE SERVICES ARE PROVIDED &amp;quot;AS IS&amp;quot; AND &amp;quot;AS AVAILABLE&amp;quot; FOR YOUR USE, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, UNLESS SUCH WARRANTIES ARE LEGALLY INCAPABLE OF EXCLUSION. RASTECH SOFTWARE, INC. EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ANY AND ALL REPRESENTATIONS AND WARRANTIES,
    WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING: (i) ALL WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, NONINFRINGEMENT, AND ANY AND ALL
    WARRANTIES ARISING FROM COURSE OF DEALING AND USAGE OF TRADE; (ii) THAT THE SERVICES, WEBSITE AND THE META CONTENT WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS, WILL ALWAYS
    BE AVAILABLE, ACCESSIBLE, UNINTERRUPTED, TIMELY, SECURE OR OPERATE WITHOUT ERROR; (iii) AS TO THE RESULTS THAT MAY BE OBTAINED FROM THE OPERATION, USE OR
    OTHER EXPLOITATION OF THE SERVICES, WEBSITE OR THE META CONTENT; AND (iv) AS TO THE ACCURACY OR RELIABILITY OF ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THE SERVICES,
    WEBSITE OR THE META CONTENT. No advice or information obtained by you from Rastech Software, Inc., or otherwise through the Services, will create any
    warranty not expressly stated herein.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. &lt;/strong&gt;
    RASTECH SOFTWARE, INC. WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND ARISING FROM THE USE OF THE SERVICE OR FROM ANY INFORMATION, META CONTENT, MATERIALS,
    PRODUCTS (INCLUDING SOFTWARE) OR SERVICES INCLUDED ON OR OTHERWISE MADE AVAILABLE TO YOU THROUGH THE SERVICE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO DIRECT,
    INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, PUNITIVE, AND CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, UNLESS OTHERWISE SPECIFIED IN WRITING.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    CERTAIN STATE LAWS DO NOT ALLOW LIMITATIONS ON IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF CERTAIN DAMAGES. IF THESE LAWS APPLY TO YOU, SOME OR
    ALL OF THE ABOVE DISCLAIMERS, EXCLUSIONS, OR LIMITATIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU, AND YOU MIGHT HAVE ADDITIONAL RIGHTS.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Indemnity. &lt;/strong&gt;
    You agree to indemnify and hold Rastech Software, Inc. and its affiliates, subsidiaries, owners, directors, officers, employees and agents harmless from
    and against any and all claims, demands, suits, proceedings, liabilities, judgments, losses, damages, expenses and costs (including without limitation
    reasonable attorneys&#39; fees) assessed or incurred by Rastech Software, Inc., directly or indirectly, with respect to or arising out of: (i) your failure to
    comply with this Agreement; (ii) your breach of your obligations under this Agreement; (iii) your use of the rights granted hereunder, including without
    limitation any claims made by any third parties; (iv) your violation of any third party right, including without limitation any intellectual property,
    right of publicity, or privacy right; and/or (v) any claim that any of your User Content caused damage to a third party.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;6. Copyright Claims&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Rastech Software, Inc. complies with the provisions of the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) applicable to internet service providers (17 U.S.C. &amp;sect;
    512, as amended), and responds to clear notices of alleged copyright infringement.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    In the event you believe that any Content on the Services infringes your copyright, then please file a notice of infringement with our designated agent:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Rastech Software, Inc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Attn: Copyright Agent
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    745 Atlantic Avenue, Boston 02111, USA
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    info@meta.sc
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Electronic notification is preferred. To be effective, any notice submitted to our Copyright Agent must comply with the requirements set forth at 17 U.S.C.
    &amp;sect; 512(c)(3). That means that the notice must include substantially the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    1. A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    2. Identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed, or, if multiple copyrighted works at a single online site are covered by a single
    notification, a representative list of such works at that site;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    3. Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which
    is to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit us to locate the material;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    4. Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which
    is to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit us to locate the material;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    5. A statement that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent,
    or the law; and
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    6. A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that you are authorized to act on behalf of the owner of
    an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If we take measures to remove or disable content, we will make a good-faith attempt to contact, if applicable, the user who uploaded the content so that he
    or she may make a counter-notification pursuant to sections 17 U.S.C. &amp;sect; 512(g). Your complaint, along with your personally identifying information, may be
    shared with the user who uploaded the content at issue. It is our policy to document all notifications of alleged infringement on which we act. As with all
    legal notices, a copy of the notification may be sent to one or more third parties who may make it available to the public. Please be advised that it is
    Company&#39;s policy to terminate the accounts of users that repeatedly violate these Terms of Use and/or the DMCA Policy.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If you are a user of the Services and User Content that you have stored on the Services has been removed or disabled, you may file a counter-notification
    pursuant to 17 U.S.C. &amp;sect; 512(g). To be effective, the counter-notification must be a written communication sent to the Copyright Agent listed above that
    includes the following:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    1. Your physical or electronic signature;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    2. Identification of the material that has been removed or to which access has been disabled, and the location at which the material appeared before it was
    removed or access to it was disabled;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    3. A statement under penalty of perjury that you have a good faith belief that the material was removed or disabled as a result of mistake or
    misidentification of the material to be removed or disabled; and
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    4. Your name, address, and telephone number, and a statement that you consent to the jurisdiction of Federal District Court for the judicial district in
    which the address is located or, if your address is outside of the United States, for any judicial district in which Company may be found, and that you
    will accept service of process from the person who provided notification under subsection 17 U.S.C. &amp;sect; 512(c)(1)(C) or an agent of such person.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;7. Applicable Law and Jurisdiction&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The Services are operated by Rastech Software, Inc. from the United States, and we do not represent or warrant that use of the Services or any component
    thereof is lawful in other jurisdictions. Access to the Service from jurisdictions where such access is illegal is prohibited. All matters arising from or
    relating to this Agreement and the use and operation of the Services shall be governed by the substantive laws of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts,
    without regard to its conflicts of laws principles. Without derogation of the obligation to arbitrate set forth in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; below,
    you agree to submit to the personal jurisdiction of the state and federal courts located in Boston, Massachusetts. If you gain access to the Services from
    locations outside the United States, you will be responsible for compliance with all local laws of any such other location, and in no event will you use
    the Services or Content in violation of U.S. export laws or regulations.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;8. Dispute Resolution&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    All disputes arising out of or relating to this Agreement or the Services that are not resolved by mutual agreement shall be resolved exclusively by
    binding arbitration before a single arbitrator (the &amp;quot;Arbitrator&amp;quot;) in accordance with the Commercial Arbitration Rules of the American Arbitration
    Association (the &amp;quot;AAA&amp;quot;) then in effect (for information on the AAA and its rules, see www.adr.org.) and the further procedures set forth herein, except
    that each party retains the right to seek injunctive or other equitable relief in a court of competent jurisdiction to prevent the actual or threatened
    infringement, misappropriation or violation of a party&#39;s copyrights, trademarks, trade secrets, patents or other intellectual property rights. The
    arbitration shall be conducted in Boston, Massachusetts, unless the Arbitrator shall determine that that venue is not reasonably convenient to all parties,
    in which case the Arbitrator shall determine another venue that is. In the event that the AAA is unavailable or unwilling to administer the arbitration,
    and the parties are unable to agree to a substitute, a substitute shall be appointed by the court. The Arbitrator shall have authority to issue any and all
    remedies authorized by law. The arbitration shall be governed by the Federal Arbitration Act, 9 U.S.C. &amp;sect;&amp;sect; 2 et seq. Notwithstanding any rules of the AAA to
    the contrary, any claims shall be adjudicated on an individual basis only, and YOU WAIVE ANY RIGHT TO BRING ANY CLAIM AS A REPRESENTATIVE OF A PROPOSED
    CLASS, ON AN AGGREGATED OR MASS BASIS, OR AS A PRIVATE ATTORNEY GENERAL, OR TO CONSOLIDATE ARBITRATION PROCEEDINGS WITHOUT THE CONSENT OF ALL PARTIES
    THERETO. Any award rendered by the Arbitrator shall be final and binding upon the parties hereto. In connection with any arbitration proceeding pursuant to
    this Agreement, unless the Arbitrator shall determine otherwise, each party shall bear its own costs and expenses. Notwithstanding the foregoing, you may
    at your option file an individual claim in any small claims court for disputes or claims within the scope of its subject matter jurisdiction if such court
    has personal jurisdiction. The provisions of this arbitration section will be enforceable in any court of competent jurisdiction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;9. Termination of Service&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    You may discontinue your use of the Services at any time. We may terminate your user account or right to access all or portions of the Services at any
    time, without notice, for any reason or for no reason or for conduct that we believe violates this Agreement and/or is harmful to other users, to Rastech
    Software, Inc., to other service or information providers, or to any third parties. After any termination of this Agreement and/or after you otherwise stop
    using the Services, the following will survive and remain enforceable and in full force and effect:
    &lt;strong&gt;
        (i) all outstanding obligations between you and us; (ii) all remedies for breach of this Agreement; and (iii) the following sections of this Agreement:
        2(a), 2(b), and 2(d) (Ownership and Content); 3 (User Content); 4 (Other Websites and Services); 5 (Warranty Disclaimers, Limitations of Liability,
        Indemnity); 7 (Applicable Law and Jurisdiction); 8 (Dispute Resolution); 9 (Termination of Service); and 10 (Miscellaneous).
    &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;10. Miscellaneous&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    No delay or omission by Rastech Software, Inc. in exercising any of its rights under this Agreement will impair any such right or be construed to be a
    waiver thereof, and a waiver by Rastech Software, Inc. of any of the covenants, conditions or agreements to be performed by you will not be construed to be
    a waiver of any succeeding breach thereof or of any other covenant, condition or agreement hereof contained. If any provision of this Agreement is found by
    a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid or unenforceable, then this Agreement will remain in full force and effect and will be reformed to be valid
    and enforceable while reflecting the intent of the parties to the greatest extent permitted by law. Except as otherwise expressly provided herein, this
    Agreement sets forth the entire agreement between you and Rastech Software, Inc. regarding its subject matter, and supersedes all prior promises,
    agreements or representations, whether written or oral, regarding such subject matter. You shall not assign or transfer this Agreement or any right or
    obligation hereunder to any third party. You agree that the electronic text of this Agreement constitutes a writing and your assent to the terms and
    conditions hereof constitutes a &amp;quot;signing&amp;quot; for all purposes.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    You consent to receive communications from us electronically, and you agree that we may communicate with you by email or by posting notices on the
    Services. You agree that all agreements, notices, disclosures and other communications that we provide to you, or that you provide to us, electronically
    satisfy any legal requirement that such communications be in writing. We are not responsible for any automatic filtering that may be applied to any email
    notices that we send to the email address you have provided.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The effective date of these Terms of Use is July 29, 2015.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta - Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 15:52:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;PRIVACY POLICY&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    This privacy policy (&amp;quot;Policy&amp;quot;) is designed to inform users of the Meta service, including all associated apps, software, and websites (collectively, the
    &amp;quot;Service&amp;quot;) about how Rastech Software, Inc. (&amp;quot;Rastech,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;we&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;us&amp;quot;) gathers and uses personal information collected by us in connection with the Service.
    We will take reasonable steps to protect user privacy consistent with the guidelines set forth in this policy and with applicable U.S. laws. In this
    policy, &amp;quot;user&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;you&amp;quot; means any person using or otherwise benefiting from the Service or otherwise submitting personal information to us via the Service.
    BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SERVICE, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND, AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO
    THESE TERMS, DO NOT USE THE SERVICE. This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference into the Meta Terms of Service, available at www.meta.sc/tos, to
    which you agree to be bound by using the Service.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;What Information Do We Collect?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Limited Personal Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We collect the following personal information in connection with the Service: (a) if you register as a Meta user, we will collect the personal
    information you submit to us to build your user profile, including your name and email address; (b) if applicable, we may collect payment information from
    such as your name and credit card information; and (c) if you communicate with us by email, we will collect your email address. All of this information is
    referred to in this Policy as &amp;quot;Personal Information.&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Other Personal Identifiers&lt;/u&gt;
    : Apart from the limited personal information described above, we do &lt;u&gt;not&lt;/u&gt; collect and does not wish to receive any personally identifying
    information. Without limitation, you shall not submit to us any social security number, financial account number, credit or debit card number (other than
    payment information provided for the Service), driver&#39;s license number or government ID number.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;User Data&lt;/u&gt;
    : When using the Service, and depending on the nature of user files and their location, user files and names and portions thereof are uploaded to the
    Service. All data uploaded by users at the direction of users is referred to in this Policy as &amp;quot;User Data.&amp;quot; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Web Tracking Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We, and our third party service providers, may use web tracking technologies such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags and clear GIFs in order to operate
    the Service efficiently and to collect data related to usage of the Service. Such collected data (&amp;quot;Web Tracking Information&amp;quot;) may include the address of
    the websites you visited before and after you visited the Service, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, what pages in
    the Service you visit and what links you clicked on, and whether you opened email communications we send to you. In order to collect Web Tracking
    Information and to make your use of the Service more efficient, we may store cookies on your computer. We may also use web tracking technologies that are
    placed in web pages on the Service or in email communications to collect information about actions that users take when they interact with the Service or
    such email communications, and our Contractors (as defined herein) may also do so. We do not correlate Web Tracking Information to individual user Personal
    Information, except for internal operational, product development, and administrative purposes of the Service. Some Web Tracking Information may include
    data, such as IP address data, that is unique to you. You may be able to modify your browser settings to alter which web tracking technologies are
    permitted when you use the Service, but this may affect the performance of the Service.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;How Do We Use the Information We Collect?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Personal Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : Your Personal Information may be supplemented with additional information regarding your activities on the Service; to the extent that such information
    is linked specifically to you, we will treat that additional information as your Personal Information. We may use your email address to send you
    informational materials regarding the Services, or marketing materials regarding Rastech&#39;s other products and services. We may also use Personal
    Information for the internal operational, product development, and administrative purposes of the Service.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;User Data&lt;/u&gt;
    : We collect and temporarily store User Data in order to provide the Service to you, and it may be used for the internal operational, product development,
    and administrative purposes of the Service. &lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Web Tracking Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We use Web Tracking Information to administer the Service and to understand how well our Service is working, to store your user preferences, and to
    develop statistical information on usage of the Service. This helps us improve our Service, personalize your user experience, and to measure overall
    effectiveness.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Aggregate Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We will also create statistical, aggregated data relating to our users and the Service for analytical purposes (&amp;quot;Aggregate Information&amp;quot;). Aggregate
    Information is derived from Personal Information and User Data but in its aggregated form it does not duplicate or reveal any User Data or relate to or
    identify any individual. This data is used to understand our customer base and to develop, improve and market the Service and our other services.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;What Information Do We Disclose to Third Parties?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Personal Information and User Data&lt;/u&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;: &lt;/em&gt;
    We will not disclose your Personal Information or User Data to any third parties except as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    (i) to third party contractors engaged to provide services on our behalf (&amp;quot;Contractors&amp;quot;), such as performing marketing, analyzing data and usage of the
    Service, hosting and operating the Service or providing support and maintenance services for the Service, or providing customer service. We enter into
agreements with all Contractors that require Contractors to use the Personal Information they receive only to perform services for us.    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    (ii) when we have your consent to share the information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Web Tracking Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We disclose Web Tracking Information to Contractors, in order to analyze the performance of the Service and the behavior of users, and to operate and
    improve the Service. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Aggregate Information&lt;/u&gt;
    : We may disclose aggregated data that does not contain Personal Information or User Data to any third parties, such as media outlets, potential customers,
    business partners, and funding sources, in order to describe our business and operations.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Network Operators&lt;/u&gt;
    : Use of the Service may involve use of the services of third party telecommunications carriers. These carriers are not our contractors, and any
    information that a carrier collects in connection with your use of the Service is not &amp;quot;Personal Information&amp;quot; and is not subject to this Privacy Policy. We
    are not responsible for the acts or omissions of telecommunications carriers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Legal Exception&lt;/u&gt;
    : Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, we may preserve or disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to
    comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect our
    rights or property. However, nothing in this Policy is intended to limit any legal defenses or objections that you may have to a third party&#39;s, including a
    government&#39;s, request to disclose your information.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Business Transfers&lt;/u&gt;
    : In the event that Rastech is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred
    as part of that transaction. This Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Privacy Settings/Opt Out&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    If you wish to modify any of your user profile information, remove your email from our mailing list, cancel your account, or change the school in which you
    are a part of, please contact us at info@meta.sc.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Your removal from our mailing list or database will not remove User Data you have submitted to us or records of past use of the Service, nor delete
    information stored in our data backups and archives. User Data, including User Data submitted, data on past queries and data stored in backups and archives
    will be maintained and/or deleted in the ordinary course of our business. Rastech does not provide copies of User Data to its customers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Security&lt;/u&gt;
    : We use reasonable security precautions to protect the security and integrity of your Personal Information in accordance with this policy and applicable
    law. However, no Internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that security breaches will not occur. Without limitation of the
    foregoing, we are not responsible for the actions of hackers and other unauthorized third parties that breach our reasonable security procedures.&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Links&lt;/u&gt;
    : The Service may contain links to other websites and services, including payment services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content
    of those websites, and you should review the privacy statements of each third party website you visit. This Policy applies solely to information collected
    by the Service.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Amendments&lt;/u&gt;
    : We may revise this Policy from time to time. The most current version of the Policy will govern our use of your information and will always be located at
    www.meta.sc/privacy. If we make a change to this Policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will notify you via the Service or via email to the
    email address associated with your account. By continuing to access or use the Service after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the
    revised Policy.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Children&lt;/u&gt;
    : We do not knowingly collect or retain personally identifiable information about persons under 13 years of age. Any person who provides their personal
    information to us via the Service represents that they are 13 years of age or older. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor the activity of
    those under 13 years of age. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personally identifiable data to us, please contact
    us, and we will make every effort to delete that information from our databases.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Service Visitors from outside the United States&lt;/u&gt;
    : Rastech and its servers are located in the United States and are subject to the applicable state and federal laws of the United States. If you choose to
    access or use the Service, you consent to the use and disclosure of information in accordance with this privacy policy and subject to such laws.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;u&gt;Effective Date of this policy&lt;/u&gt;
    : July 30, 2015
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Clean</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/tech/startclean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 03:01:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/tech/startclean/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When we started off designing the cloud architecture for Meta in February of 2015, it was with a totally clean slate. We had a vision for the experience that we wanted to create and requirements to go along with that, but no constraints from previously built technology or legacy infrastructure. While not an atypical position for a startup, we were thus positioned to choose a technology stack that fit our goals exactly while catering to the capabilities of our small team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;product-requirements:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Product Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin building out a product that matched the vision we had for Meta, we first had to outline what was required to build our product. A good starting point for this was the interactions we envisioned for users. Firstly, users should be able to search for their files and get back highly relevant results. Additionally, our system  must be able to perform analysis on the content of files to extract meaningful tags and metadata facilitating organization and our search. Lastly, we must be able to open a user&amp;rsquo;s files for them no matter the location of the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting at core of all this functionality is the ability to maintain centralized knowledge of where a user&amp;rsquo;s files are at all times, and to keep that snapshot always up to date. This presents a situation that is a little different from the challenge faced by most products. Rather than determining the best way to define resources unique to our system, we had to determine the best way to represent externally defined resources across an immense variety of systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our technology choices in building out our core infrastructure to solve these problems will be the topic of this blog post, enumerating our choices for the technology that Meta is built on and the motivations underlying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;formulating-an-architecture:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Formulating an Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boiling down the options for building a cloud application into a dichotomy, you have a choice between a monolith or microservices. Since we were starting our application from scratch with a goal of building out an MVP, starting with a monolithic application had a certain appealing features. We could punt on certain problems of scalability in order to focus on building something that works and then validate our idea with customers. Still, looking at the future of such a system presented problems. The concept of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/SacrificialArchitecture.html&#34;&gt;sacrificial architecture&lt;/a&gt; seemed like a painful transition for a system that was as distributed in nature as ours, and when you have a system that interfaces with such a wide variety of inputs as our does, it is pretty much impossible to create anything truly monolithic since we are receiving information form so many sources. Thus, even if we built a central monolith, we would still be working in a highly distributed environment, eroding some of the simplicity of a truly monolithic architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, implementing microservices in the fullest sense incurs significant development cost. Something that would otherwise be a simple function call turns into a network request, and a large number of APIs need to be well designed to encapsulate each piece of functionality in the system. Established companies, such as the classic example of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/blog/microservices-at-netflix-architectural-best-practices/&#34;&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, utilize hundreds of microservices to provide their services. Building an infrastructure with that amount of granularity from the start would be a bit foolish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to start off with an architecture that would facilitate transitioning to true microservices. Our current system has around a dozen separate services, and building with the design principles of service oriented architectures in mind will allow our application to be further subdivided in the future. Additionally, we were picking our technology stack in parallel with formulating our system architecture, so the flexibility of microservices to mix and match programming languages to suit specific problems was enticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;surveying-language-choices:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Surveying Language Choices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our primary goals for Meta&amp;rsquo;s UX is that our cloud based product should feel as fast and responsive as the interactions our customers are used to on a computer. In terms of our core architecture, this meant that changes occurring on your local machine should propagate through our system as quickly as possible. The system we are building is by nature eventually consistent; changes made to a files on user&amp;rsquo;s computer will always take some amount of time to propagate up to the our UI, but those changes must happen as quickly as possible, ideally fast enough for it to be perceived as instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To facilitate reaching this goal, we needed to build out our architecture on a programming language that was lightning fast by default. We needed to have a baseline of response times in the tens of milliseconds, not in the hundreds. Our focus for the core infrastructure was thus shifted away from dynamic languages and heavier duty frameworks and towards more customizable and performance focused technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;c-c:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;C/C++&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When thinking about performance critical languages, C/C++ is probably the first thing that comes to mind. Developers are given precise and powerful control over the way that their application runs, and if done well the resulting applications are incredibly capable and performant. Still, these gains over didn&amp;rsquo;t outweigh the increase in complexity and potential for bugs. C/C++ didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a great starting point to build an MVP of a cloud system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;java-scala:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Java/Scala&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JVM based languages offer speed and efficiency while eschewing manual memory management and other headaches of lower level languages. They have a mature and powerful ecosystem to support their products. Furthermore, during the summer of 2014 a proof of concept for Meta had been built out entirely in Scala, providing a code base that we could potentially leverage to speed up the development of our MVP. We actually did start off writing pieces of our application in Scala, but a few hiccups deterred us from pursuing it further. First of all, while the JVM is powerful, the complexity associated with deploying and tuning applications with complex build and dependency systems added overhead. Secondly, hiring great Scala developers is hard. While immensely powerful and expressive, the time it takes for a developer to get up to speed is much larger than for alternatives. The deal breaker was a lack of support for up to date Java technologies on on our chosen cloud platform, which I&amp;rsquo;ll get to shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;go:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Go!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go is the new kid on the block. Several things about it seemed like a good for for us. First of all, its performance was on par with JVM based languages despite its young age. We were also attracted to its simplicity and focus on explicit behavior. As our system grows in complexity, being able to track down issues across code bases would be increasingly important, and thus being able to approach code written by others is a helpful aspect of the language. Tools like &lt;code&gt;go fmt&lt;/code&gt; help enforce a uniform style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Go is a simple language that can be learned in a matter of weeks, opening up our hiring requirements significantly. Still, that simplicity is not without costs. While some language features like higher order functions and the powerful concurrency primitives are top notch, there are areas where &lt;a href=&#34;http://yager.io/programming/go.html&#34;&gt;it is lacking&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately though, for the class of problems we are working in, Go is a great fit for the core problems that we&amp;rsquo;re working on. We&amp;rsquo;ve been delighted with the language so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment-and-infrastructure:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Deployment and Infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lost track of the time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent on various projects tinkering with server configuration files into the early hours of the morning, endeavoring to get some piece of infrastructure up and running or back online. While options such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, and tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chef.io&#34;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://puppetlabs.com&#34;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt; can make this process easier and more automated, there is still a hump to get over before they start paying dividends. Some emerging technologies like &lt;a href=&#34;http://nixos.org&#34;&gt;NixOS&lt;/a&gt;, a functional and declarative operating system, seemed exciting, but I wanted to ensure that we spent our scarce development time focusing on the problems unique to our product rather than ones of infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this desire, PaaS (platform as a service) offerings had a lot of appeal. Since we had chosen Go as our primary development language, supporting it was a key criteria. A number of PaaS offerings are available on this front which we were evaluating in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One platform coming into it&amp;rsquo;s own was Google App Engine. Since Go came out of Google, support for that language seemed like it was on a good path (validated by it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/google-appengine-go/as9wUqT77YU&#34;&gt;move to general availability&lt;/a&gt; recently!). When they offered us a spectacular credits program for established startups, we decided to go with App Engine. The microservices based design of our application allowed us to alleviate concerns about vendor lock-in, since any migration could be executed piece by piece and we could even split our infrastructure across providers if deemed necessary. While we may move away from PaaS solutions to options that give us more control over our application in the future, the ability to focus all our mental energy on the core of our product has been immensely valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions:9849efcacdcb3a3ca94c1ee29050eb1c&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing technology for an application is a difficult and often nebulous choice. There is no single right answer so questions about ways to do things better can always be raised and are healthy for the growth of product. Still, it seems that about once a week I come across an article about how X tech company just moved away from Y heavy duty framework to Z, giving them massive performance gains and cost savings. Pleasantly, the &amp;ldquo;Z&amp;rdquo; is often Go, validating our initial choices to a degree. While our initial launch may have been slightly slowed down by our focus on building a service based application that can scale effectively, we haven&amp;rsquo;t questioned that decision for a second. If you have confidence in a validated need for what you are building, start your product right and build your out a scalable architecture. Not something that can scale to millions of users tomorrow, but something that can grow and be expanded on by your team to facilitate the growth of your company. At Meta, we&amp;rsquo;re in the midst of roll out for our closed Beta and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see where our platform can take us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the challenges we&amp;rsquo;re facing interest you, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.sc&#34;&gt;careers page&lt;/a&gt; and drop us a line at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:careers@meta.sc&#34;&gt;careers@meta.sc&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re hiring in every area of software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>example</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/features/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 15:05:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/features/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a placeholder for features if we decide to have them generated rather than purely static&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating Idiomatic Swift with Objective-C</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/tech/swiftobjc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 09:38:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/tech/swiftobjc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At Meta, most of the work that has gone into our client applications thus far facilitates keeping our user’s files in sync with our cloud system so that they can be easily searched and accessed. When we began work on the client application for Mac OS X a few months ago, there were two major decisions that had to be made. The first was how to organize the application so that a resilient background process could listen for file system changes and keep everything up to date in the cloud. I’ll likely be discussing that in a future post. The second decision was what language to base the project in, which I will be discussing here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was to be the primary developer of this application for the short term, this was partly a personal choice. While most of my experience in Apple&amp;rsquo;s world to date had been in writing Objective-C code, I had experimented with Swift and was excited to try it out in a production application. The were a few features in particular that I was attracted to in Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start with, Swift&amp;rsquo;s concision was especially enticing. The ability to express oneself quickly is a desirable feature in any language, and fewer lines of code written means fewer lines of code to maintain. Another area of interest was the type safety, which Swift makes available through its data structures. Our system is largely event-based, with relatively complex data types passing information around about the state of a user&amp;rsquo;s files. In the back end, our use of structs provided by &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; provides strong type safety in handling incoming data. Being able to work with similar guarantees on the client side is highly desirable. A third aspect that was appealing to me personally was the functional aspects of Swift. I enjoy programming in a functional style and Swift&amp;rsquo;s built in functionality for &lt;code&gt;map&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;reduce&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;join&lt;/code&gt;, and the like were a great stimulus to try out the language further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the decision was made to use Swift as the primary language, development of our Mac application moved forward rapidly. Once the various components of the application were in place and structured, I began work on the meat of the application: handling changes to a user&amp;rsquo;s files. To interface with the file system on the level we required, much of the interaction occurs within the Core Foundation frameworks and in pure C code. As we tried to interface with these frameworks in Swift, a variety of issues came up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;interfacing-with-uttype:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Interfacing with UTType&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical to analyzing a file&amp;rsquo;s content and displaying a meaningful description of a file to the user is knowing what kind of file you are dealing with. Cocoa&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/MobileCoreServices/Reference/UTTypeRef/&#34;&gt;UTType&lt;/a&gt; functionality provides us with the ability to extrapolate a file&amp;rsquo;s MIME type for use in our cloud services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;swift:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Swift, my best attempt at interfacing with UTType is as follows in the code snippet below. There are two calls into the &lt;code&gt;UTType&lt;/code&gt; framework. The first requires a parameter of type &lt;code&gt;CFStringRef&lt;/code&gt;, which is easily created with a cast which utilized toll-free bridging behinds the scenes. The return value of this function is &lt;code&gt;Unmanaged&amp;lt;CFString&amp;gt;!&lt;/code&gt;, indicating that is an unannotated method where the memory management must be manually handled in Swift. The &lt;code&gt;takeRetainedValue()&lt;/code&gt; function is used because the value returned by this function as already been retained and needs to be released when the current scope is exited, thus removing the &lt;code&gt;Unmanaged&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; wrapper from the inner type. Additionally, the failure case I have here is rather convoluted because it occurs when the &lt;code&gt;cfMimeType&lt;/code&gt; fails to bridge to a string, rather than explicitly from the return of the function call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;// this code crashes at runtime
public class func mimeTypeForFile(path: String) -&amp;gt; String {
    let ext = path.pathExtension as CFStringRef
    let UTI = UTTypeCreatePreferredIdentifierForTag(kUTTagClassFilenameExtension, ext, nil).takeRetainedValue()
    
    let cfMimeType = UTTypeCopyPreferredTagWithClass(UTI, kUTTagClassMIMEType).takeRetainedValue()
    if let mimeType = cfMimeType as? String {
        return mimeType
    }
    return &amp;quot;application/octet-stream&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got this code compiling, I wrote a short unit test. Unfortunately when this code is run the following error occurs, a dreaded &lt;code&gt;EXC_BAD_INSTRUCTION&lt;/code&gt; runtime error. It is certainly possible that this code could be further massaged to get this example working (please let me know if you are able to), but after a good half hour or so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%;position:relative;&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/blog/images/snippets/swift_uttype.png&#34; alt=&#34;Swift UTType interfacing&#34; title=&#34;Optional title&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;objective-c:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Objective-C&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the same code in Objective-C, several things are more desirable. Firstly, this code works; usually a desirable attribute in production code. No bad instructions errors here. Secondly, coming from a background of Objective-C, what is happening here is clearer than in the Swift code. Rather than dealing with wrappers on Core Foundation types meant to insulate Swift from pointers, you are dealing with the implementation directly and the underlying interactions are clearer. Since most developers writing Swift are coming from an Objective-C background, it should be explicitly clear what this code is doing in regard to memory management and error handling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objectivec&#34;&gt;- (NSString*) mimeTypeForFile:(NSString*) path {
    CFStringRef ext = (__bridge CFStringRef)[path pathExtension];
    CFStringRef UTI = UTTypeCreatePreferredIdentifierForTag(kUTTagClassFilenameExtension, ext, NULL);
    CFStringRef mimeType = UTTypeCopyPreferredTagWithClass(UTI, kUTTagClassMIMEType);
    CFRelease(UTI);
    if (!mimeType) {
        return @&amp;quot;application/octet-stream&amp;quot;;
    }
    return CFBridgingRelease(mimeType);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;file-system-events:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;File System Events&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another area where we ran into issues was in our use of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Conceptual/FSEvents_ProgGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html&#34;&gt;File System Events API&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a stream giving callbacks to your application when anything changes on the file system within a specified scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows is my best attempt to create File System Event stream in pure Swift. There is a lot of syntactic baggage surrounding pointer handling and Core Foundation types, but theoretically all that should work just fine. The blocking issue is that a &lt;code&gt;CFuntionPointer&lt;/code&gt;, Swift&amp;rsquo;s type which is analogous to a normal function pointer in pure C code, cannot be created from either a Swift function or a closure. This is a limitation of the Swift language (until the recent 2.0 release, more on that later). The following code fails to compile because of this limitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;// this code does not compile
func testCreateSimpleSwiftListener() {
    let cfDirs = [NSHomeDirectory()] as CFArray
    let context = nil as UnsafeMutablePointer&amp;lt;FSEventStreamContext&amp;gt;
    let latency = 3.0 as CFAbsoluteTime
    let flags = kFSEventStreamCreateFlagFileEvents | kFSEventStreamCreateFlagWatchRoot
    
    let callback: @objc_block (
    ConstFSEventStreamRef,
    UnsafeMutablePointer&amp;lt;Void&amp;gt;,
    Int,
    UnsafeMutablePointer&amp;lt;Void&amp;gt;,
    UnsafePointer&amp;lt;FSEventStreamEventFlags&amp;gt;,
    UnsafePointer&amp;lt;FSEventStreamEventId&amp;gt;) -&amp;gt; Void = {
        (streamRef, clientCallBackInfo, numEvents, eventPaths, eventFlags, eventIds) -&amp;gt; Void in
        NSLog(&amp;quot;Received %i paths&amp;quot;, numEvents)
        // handle file event
    } as CFunctionPointer
    
    let stream = FSEventStreamCreate(
        kCFAllocatorDefault,
        callback as FSEventStreamCallback,
        context,
        cfDirs,
        kFSEventStreamEventIdSinceNow,
        latency,
        flags
    )
    FSEventStreamScheduleWithRunLoop(stream, CFRunLoopGetCurrent(), kCFRunLoopDefaultMode)
    FSEventStreamStart(stream)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the code with the compiler errors shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:100%;position:relative;&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/blog/images/snippets/swift_fsevents_func.png&#34; alt=&#34;Swift FSEvents interfacing&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, with some further massaging this &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/25514176/using-swift-cfunctionpointer-to-pass-a-callback-to-coremidi-api#answer-29375116&#34;&gt;might&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.eltima.com/post/97718928834/interacting-with-c-pointers-in-swift-part-3&#34;&gt;might not&lt;/a&gt; be possible by delving further into the Objective-C runtime, but in doing so we yet again lose out on the most of the benefits of working in Swift at all. Even with this function pointer issue fixed, the &lt;code&gt;UnsafeMutablePointer&amp;lt;Type&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UnsafePointer&amp;lt;Type&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; wrappers are uncomfortable to work with and a jarring change from the kind of Swift code that one can enjoy writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reclaiming-the-benefits-of-swift:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Reclaiming the benefits of Swift&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the previous two examples, nearly all of the reasons that I chose Swift for this project in the first place have been eroded to some degree. With the wrappers around low level objects, much of the concision disappeared. Since we are using Core Foundation types, type safety within data structures has withered. Lastly, higher level language features can only be applied after these low level types have been sufficiently dealt with. It basically feels like writing C code with more verbose and unfamiliar syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, when we are writing Swift we can focus on the benefits of the language, not how it interfaces with the very code it was meant to replace. The solution we ended up using here is to wrap interactions with Core Foundation and C APIs with simple Objective-C wrapper classes that provide a clean API for use by your Swift code. For us, this consisted primarily of two basic classes, &lt;code&gt;FileSystemListener&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FileSystemCrawler&lt;/code&gt;. The listener class is a wrapper around code dealing with the aforementioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Conceptual/FSEvents_ProgGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html&#34;&gt;File System Events API&lt;/a&gt;, and the crawler wraps low level C code with interacts with the file system as efficiently as possible, enabling introspectable breadth-first crawls that can handle concurrent modifications to the file system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By providing these interfaces, the rest of our Swift code can interact with a purpose built API that dovetails nicely into our business logic, written in Swift, feeding changes to our events streams in the cloud. Additionally, it helps to reinforce good design principles in the realm of code modularity and separation of concerns, making your application more maintainable and testable moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective-c-and-swift:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Objective-C and Swift&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interop between Objective-C and Swift at a higher level is a much friendlier affair, and most developers working in Swift probably have some experience in this area. Still, at the risk of paraphrasing the documentation, there were a few areas which were of particular interest to us that I would like to touch on. If this is an area where you are working in-depth, I would recommend that you to consult Apple&amp;rsquo;s documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/index.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014216-CH2-XID_0&#34;&gt;Using Swift with Cocoa and Objective-C&lt;/a&gt; directly for a much more thorough treatment of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;bridging:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Bridging&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis for interop between Objective-C and Swift is bridging between the two languages. Calling into Objective-C from Swift requires a bridging header to be inserted into your project, which Xcode will usually prompt you for, as shown below, when an Objective-C file is added to a Swift project. This file is linked to your build settings in the &lt;strong&gt;Swift Compiler - Code Generation&lt;/strong&gt; section as the &lt;strong&gt;Objective-C Bridging Header&lt;/strong&gt;. This header file contains import statements for the header files of Objective-C code that you wish to interact with. The Objective-C file that prompted its creation will be automatically added, and all subsequent files must be added manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/Art/bridgingheader_2x.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%;position:relative;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;syntactic-translation:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Syntactic Translation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/InteractingWithObjective-CAPIs.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014216-CH4-XID_25&#34;&gt;documented&lt;/a&gt;, the Swift compiler performs translations of Objective-C syntax into Swift so that initializers, methods, and function calls can be performed natively from Swift code. Most of these conversions are fairly intuitive, and you have probably worked with some examples of these translations. The below example is a simplified version of a delegate of our &lt;code&gt;FileSystemListener&lt;/code&gt; class that wraps the FSEvents library using Objective-C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objc&#34;&gt;@protocol FileSystemListenerDelegate &amp;lt;NSObject&amp;gt;
-(void)fileCreateEvent:(FSEventStreamEventId)eventID atPath:(NSString*)path withFlags:(FSEventStreamEventFlags)flags;
-(void)fileModifyEvent:(FSEventStreamEventId)eventID atPath:(NSString*)path withFlags:(FSEventStreamEventFlags)flags;
-(void)fileRemoveEvent:(FSEventStreamEventId)eventID atPath:(NSString*)path withFlags:(FSEventStreamEventFlags)flags
@end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stub of a Swift class demonstrates how the syntax translates between the two languages. Perhaps the translations are a bit more verbose than they could be, but it is still perfectly understandable and functional. And of course, Xcode&amp;rsquo;s auto complete functionality will fill out the translated function as you type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;class FileHandler: FileSystemListenerDelegate {
    func fileCreateEvent(eventID: FSEventStreamEventId, atPath path: String!, withFlags flags: FSEventStreamEventFlags) {}
    func fileModifyEvent(eventID: FSEventStreamEventId, atPath path: String!, withFlags flags: FSEventStreamEventFlags) {}
    func fileRemoveEvent(eventID: FSEventStreamEventId, atPath path: String!, withFlags flags: FSEventStreamEventFlags) {}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;initializer-behavior:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Initializer behavior&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One behavior to be cognizant of in this translation is the handling of Optional types from potentially failable Objective-C initializers. Since Objective-C does not have a concept of Optionals, the default translation is auto-unwrapped Types, indicated with a bang at the end of the type, e.g. &lt;code&gt;Type!&lt;/code&gt;. Some APIs are annotated to indicate whether or not the initialization can fail, either eschewing an Optional wrapper of prompting the use of a normal Optional. For those that are not, the way auto-unwrapped Optionals work is that when accessed, the underlying value is implicitly unwrapped, causing a panic if the underlying value happens to be nil. If you are coming from an Objective-C background where we can happily send messages to &lt;code&gt;nil&lt;/code&gt; objects and move right along, this is definitely something to watch out for. As usual, this behavior is &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/InteractingWithObjective-CAPIs.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014216-CH4-XID_27&#34;&gt;well documented&lt;/a&gt; within Apple&amp;rsquo;s treatment of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;data-types:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Data Types&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One area of concern in designing an interface between Objective-C and C code is the loss of type information for data structures. As I mentioned previously, one of the most attractive features in Swift initially was preserving type information, as opposed to untyped &lt;code&gt;NSArray&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;NSDictionary&lt;/code&gt; objects. In the current release of Swift, these are still issues, but with a bit of care they can be handled gracefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following code snippet shows a simple example of optionally casting a &lt;code&gt;NSDictionary&lt;/code&gt; into a typed Swift dictionary. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/WorkingWithCocoaDataTypes.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014216-CH6-XID_47&#34;&gt;collection classes documentation&lt;/a&gt; has further examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;let d = NSDictionary(object: &amp;quot;value&amp;quot;, forKey: &amp;quot;key&amp;quot;)
if let data = d as? [String: String] {
    print(&amp;quot;data: \(data)&amp;quot;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very simple example of bridging between the &lt;code&gt;NSString&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; types by casting. When working with strings, methods for both &lt;code&gt;NSString&lt;/code&gt; and the builtin Swift &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; types are available. Yet again, you can checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/WorkingWithCocoaDataTypes.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP40014216-CH6-XID_44&#34;&gt;strings documentation&lt;/a&gt; for further examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;let n = &amp;quot;my string&amp;quot; as NSString
let s = n as String
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cocoapods:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Cocoapods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use Cocoapods for third party dependency management in the Meta client application. When experimenting with pods that are written in Swift, we came across an interesting aspect of the tool that I had previously been unaware of. Cocoapods has historically used static libraries, because while Mac has supported dynamic libraries for some time now, iOS has only supported them since the release of Swift. Static libraries work well for Objective-C, but as described by a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cocoapods.org/CocoaPods-0.36/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the release of Cocoapods 0.36, dynamic libraries are a requirement for Cocoapods written in Swift. The use of dynamic libraries is enabled by a &lt;code&gt;use_frameworks!&lt;/code&gt; line in your &lt;code&gt;Podfile&lt;/code&gt; specifying that your pods should be dynamically linked. If you have further interest in this topic, their &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cocoapods.org/Pod-Authors-Guide-to-CocoaPods-Frameworks/&#34;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt; further illustrates the distinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-lingering-issue:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;A Lingering Issue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, when you move up out of interactions with Core Foundation and C code, interop between Objective-C and Swift just works. However, somewhere along the line we introduced a crash of the Swift compiler when building for release with optimizations, which is fixed by turning off the compiler optimizations, setting &lt;strong&gt;Optimization Level&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;-Onone&lt;/strong&gt; in the &lt;strong&gt;Swift Compiler - Code Generation&lt;/strong&gt; section. When I gave this talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Boston-Swift/&#34;&gt;Boston Swift&lt;/a&gt;, an audience member brought up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=“optimize.sil.never”&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;twitter discussion&lt;/a&gt; pointing to an annotation which may be useful in tracking down this bug. I&amp;rsquo;ll be diving into this in the coming weeks as we approach our closed beta launch, and if a solution is found I&amp;rsquo;ll post an update. Compiler optimizations can make an orders of magnitude difference in the performance of a program, so turning them off completely is quite undesirable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Swift compiler crash](https://meta.sc/images/blog/snippets/swift_compiler_error.png) --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with a new language, the last thing you want to do is try to code in the style of another language in a way that is non idiomatic. As a general rule of thumb, approaching a new language that way almost always results in less performant and less elegant code. In Swift, a lot of effort has been put in to ensure that developers can continue to interact with the existing C-based ecosystem surrounding Apple&amp;rsquo;s developer tools. While these tools are very useful for certain situations, they are far from a panacea where everything can be done in Swift. Choose your tools for the problem at hand, and when it comes to Mac and iOS development, that can mean thoughtful separation of concerns that allows you to have Swift and Objective-C existing within a simple application in a way that plays to the strengths of each language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;===&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;updates-after-wwdc-2015:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Updates after WWDC 2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The development work underlying this blog post all took place before the 2015 WWDC conference last week. Two changes in particular help with some of the issues that are described above and I am very excited about trying them out within our application. With our preparations for the beta launch I have not yet had time to do so, but I&amp;rsquo;ll give my first impressions about the benefits they present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;objective-c-generics:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Objective-C Generics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the ongoing concerns I had with using Objective-C as opposed to Swift was the lack of type safety in data types. This has always been the status quo with Objective-C, but with the latest release of the Xcode 7 beta, support has been added for Objective-C generics, which will translate into typed Swift data structures. This is an exciting new feature and a great indicator that Apple is still putting significant effort into the development of Objective-C as well as Swift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightweight generics allow you to specify type information for collection classes like NSArray, NSSet, and NSDictionary. The type information improves Swift access when you bridge from Objective-C and simplifies the code you have to write. (6294649)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cfunctionpointer-support:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;CFunctionPointer support&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central issue that blocked our efforts to use pure Swift was a lack of support for the &lt;code&gt;CFunctionPointer&lt;/code&gt; type. With the newest Xcode 7 beta release, support for function pointers has been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Native support for C function pointers: C functions that take function pointer arguments can be called using closures or global functions, with the restriction that the closure must not capture any of its local context. (16339559)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting change that would theoretically enable us to port the File System Events interactions to Swift. In combination with generics, many of my primary concerns have been alleviated. However, I think that the benefits of creating wrapper classes around these lower level APIs still hold. By abstracting away the complexity of the underlying functionality and providing a higher level API specific to your application, your code is more modular and more easily understandable. As Apple seeks to fortify Swift&amp;rsquo;s abilities, many of the issues I have run into will be undoubtedly be fixed. While the choice of language may fall more to the developer&amp;rsquo;s preference in the future, the principles of modularity will always apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we grow our team here at Meta, we want to make it as easy as possible for our newest team members to get up to speed and shipping code to our customers. If you&amp;rsquo;re interest in helping us simplify the complex and unsolved problem of finding files, reach out to us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:careers@meta.sc&#34;&gt;careers@meta.sc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slides:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post is based on a talk I gave for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Boston-Swift/&#34;&gt;Boston Swift&lt;/a&gt;. The slides are up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/AaronTaylor20/swift-objc-49480894&#34;&gt;Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/Bjr9W8CdCKOURA&#34; width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading:ed2493891a91270524d133e14b0956ee&#34;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/WorkingWithCocoaDataTypes.html&#34;&gt;Using Swift with Cocoa and Objective-C: Working with Cocoa Data Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/InteractingWithCAPIs.html&#34;&gt;Using Swift with Cocoa and Objective-C: Interacting with C APIs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/BuildingCocoaApps/MixandMatch.html&#34;&gt;Using Swift with Cocoa and Objective-C: Swift and Objective-C in the Same Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/swift/blog/?id=6&#34;&gt;Interacting with C Pointers - Swift Blog - Apple Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.eltima.com/post/93497713759/interacting-with-c-pointers-in-swift-part-2&#34;&gt;Mac Developers Blog - Interacting with C Pointers in Swift. Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.charlessoft.com/hacks/using_c_function_pointers_in_swift.html&#34;&gt;Horrible Coding Hack: Using C Function Pointers in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cocoapods.org/CocoaPods-0.36/&#34;&gt;CocoaPods 0.36 - Framework and Swift Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cocoapods.org/Pod-Authors-Guide-to-CocoaPods-Frameworks/&#34;&gt;Pod Authors Guide to CocoaPods Frameworks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://adcdownload.apple.com/WWDC_2015/Xcode_7_beta/Xcode_7_beta_Release_Notes.pdf&#34;&gt;Xcode 7 beta release notes&lt;/a&gt; (requires apple developer account)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Meta</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/blog/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 10:47:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/blog/meta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have seen our website, you know what we promise; Meta will allow you to access any file in seconds, no matter where it’s stored. But what exactly is Meta?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re pleased to give you a first glance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%;position:relative;left:25%;&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/images/blog/applogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Meta Cloud&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta is a one-of-a-kind web service that provides you with a single portal to all of your digital files, whether they’re stored in your Documents folder, Google Drive, Dropbox, or your email inbox. Plus, Meta automatically organizes all of your files for you so you can stay focused on what’s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of your files, one place to search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you forget if you saved that file on Google Drive, Dropbox, or in your Documents folder? No Problem! Meta links with your Google Drive, Dropbox, Evernote, and OneDrive accounts, as well as your computers, devices, and hard drives, so you can search for and access files on any of these platforms with Meta. Meta doesn’t store or move any of your files; it simply gives you better access to them. Say goodbye to opening multiple tabs and clicking in and out of different folders to get to a document. With Meta, you’ll be able to access all of your files from a single interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get organized without the hassle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get it. You have hundreds (or thousands) of documents on your computer. You receive email attachments every day. Who could be expected to stay on top of all these files? With Meta’s SmartTagging technology, you won’t have to. Meta automatically tags all of your documents for you so you don’t have to take time out of your day to organize. The best part? Meta learns from your behavior and preferences so its SmartTag suggestions get better the more you use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Access any file instantly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta’s lightning fast search will get you to any file you’re looking for right away, no matter where it’s stored. Even better, Meta allows you to open the file in your favorite applications. No more read-only previews, downloading duplicates, or converting Word Documents to Google Docs. Open files directly from Meta in the applications you’re familiar with so you can go straight from searching for a file to editing it. Plus, Meta ranks your search results so the file you’re looking for is always right at the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Search without the memorization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t remember what you named a file? Or specific content from the file? We’ve got you covered! Meta’s powerful search uses not only keywords to search for files, but concepts as well. Never miss a file because you forgot to type an apostrophe (true story). And since Meta is the first service that manages all of your files (local, cloud, mobile - you name it!) you won’t even have to remember where to start your search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay focused&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t stop what you’re doing to organize. With Meta, the tagging process is seamlessly integrated into your workflow. A couple clicks each time you download, create, or receive a new file will keep you completely organized- and you’ll never have to open or close a window. With Meta, you’ll spend less time processing files and more time working with them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t take our word for it! Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meta.sc/index.html#footer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a chance to participate in our beta release and experience the benefits of Meta firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Taming Your Inbox</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/blog/inboxtaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 10:47:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/blog/inboxtaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you frightened of opening your inbox? Do you receive dozens of emails each day? Does the sight of your email buildup make you physically ill? Does your phone vibrate nonstop, taunting you with the amount of emails you’ll have to deal with later? If you answered yes to any of the above, these handy email tips are for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;width:50%;position:relative;left:25%;&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/images/blog/inbox.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cluttered Inbox&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Deal with emails right away&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;I know it’s hard. Sometimes an email requires a long response (or an unpleasant one!) But the best way to beat the buildup is to deal with emails as soon as you get them. The minute you start putting off dealing with emails, your inbox starts spiraling out of control. “Dealing with” doesn’t necessarily involve a response - it could mean deleting an email you no longer need, archiving an email you might need to reference later, or forwarding an email for someone else to deal with. Just as long as you get it out of your inbox.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Schedule a block of time each day for email&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Dealing with emails right away isn’t always feasible (especially if you receive tons of emails). If you whipped out your laptop or phone the second you received an email, you wouldn’t get anything else done. Instead, set aside a block (or two) of time each day for dealing with the emails you have accumulated since your last email session. This way, you’ll still tackle your inbox without having it take over your life. This is also a great way to boost your productivity - you’ll have uninterrupted blocks of time between email sessions to get things done.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;

                        &lt;p&gt;Filter incoming emails&lt;/p&gt;


                        &lt;p&gt;Gmail’s filters are a great way to help process incoming emails (and retroactively organize old ones!) If you go to your Gmail settings under the Filters tab, you can automatically select emails based on subject, sender, whether they contain certain words, whether they include an attachment, etc. Then you can perform a number of actions on these emails - star, archive, delete, apply a label - and more! These actions will occur automatically anytime an incoming email matches the criteria so you’re one step closer to tackling your out-of-control inbox. &lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;images/filtersettings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Filter Settings&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;images/filter.png&#34; alt=&#34;Filter&#34;&gt;

                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Archive&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;There are always emails you can’t bring yourself to delete. Maybe an email contains an important attachment or the address of an upcoming meeting. Or maybe you just want to save a certain correspondence for your records. Whatever the case, these emails are cluttering your inbox. This is a great time to use the archive feature. Archiving an email removes it from your primary inbox (so you’re one step closer to achieving the elusive Inbox Zero) but doesn’t delete it. You can still access the email easily enough when you need it, but it won’t clutter your inbox in the meantime. If your email service doesn’t have an archive feature, folders are another option to cut down the clutter.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Bonus: Gmail’s Send and Archive feature&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;images/sendandarchive_zoom.png&#34; alt=&#34;Send and Archive&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;As an added bonus for Gmail users, you can enable the Send and Archive button for outgoing emails. Whenever you respond to a message in a thread, you’ll have the option to Send and Archive (as well as just Send). This will send your reply and archive the thread, getting it out of your inbox. The thread will reappear in your inbox only when the recipient writes back to you. The Send and Archive feature can be enabled in your Gmail settings in the General tab.
                        &lt;/p&gt;

                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Get a firm answer&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;This is a tip I learned from my mom (when I would always ask her for help with important emails!) Instead of responding with “I’d love to set up a meeting with you sometime,” write “I’d love to meet with you sometime this week. I’m free Wednesday afternoon and Thursday morning.” This is great for two reasons. First of all, it greatly cuts down on correspondence. The recipient will either agree to your date or propose another. Second, it helps get a date on the calendar. You are much more likely to get a meeting with someone ASAP if you suggest a date and time than if you vaguely say you’d like to meet and leave it open ended.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Gmail’s undo send feature&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;images/undo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Undo Send&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;This one’s a personal favorite of mine. You just finished an important email (to a boss, prospective employer, or investor). You click send - and then you see it! A glaring typo smack in the middle of the email. Wish you could unsend the email? With the undo send feature, now you can! Simply go to your Gmail settings, navigate to the Labs tab, and enable the Undo Send feature (don’t forget to click Save Changes at the bottom of the page!) Now, every time you click the send button, your email won’t actually send for a few seconds. The option to “Undo” will appear at the top of your window. If you go to the General tab in your Gmail settings, you can set the amount of time you are able to undo send (10 seconds works for me!)&lt;/p&gt;
                        
                        
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;Relax!&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;A lot of people struggle with this one (including me!) When you write an important email, it’s easy to hesitate when it’s time to press send. You reread it again and again, and maybe even leave it in your drafts folder overnight while you think it over. In the meantime, the email is cluttering your inbox. Don’t overthink it! Proofreading and editing are obviously a must, but obsessing too much over an email costs you time. The recipient won’t examine the email as carefully as you will.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Easy Tricks to Boost Your Productivity</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/blog/productivitytips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 10:47:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/blog/productivitytips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here at Meta, we love being organized and productive! Sadly, this is easier said than done. But fear not! We’ve compiled some of our favorite tips and tricks to help you crush this week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/images/blog/organized.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Organized Desktop&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“Failing to plan is planning to fail.”&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As harsh as it sounds, our friend Alan Lakein was definitely onto something! It requires a little extra time and effort, but a little planning goes a long way! Spend 10-15 minutes each night planning the next day. Use your planner, the calendar on your phone, a sticky note, a sheet of paper, the back of your hand - whatever! Just make sure you write your schedule somewhere. You’ll never have to stop in the middle of the day and wonder what you should do next - you’ll already have laid everything out the night before!
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Prioritize!&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;No matter how nicely you plan your day, things don’t always go according to plan. Something unexpected will come up or a project will take longer than you thought. Don’t despair! Every day, set one item on your schedule as the most important. If you do nothing else that day, you’ll feel better knowing you accomplished the most important task.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Take breaks&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Working at 100% for hours on end is unrealistic. Schedule frequent breaks throughout your day. They don’t have to be long - get up and stretch, grab a snack, take a quick walk - just something to give your mind and body a quick break. You’ll feel rejuvenated when it’s time to get back to business! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themuse.com/advice/the-rule-of-52-and-17-its-random-but-it-ups-your-productivity&#34;&gt; This post &lt;/a&gt; from the Muse has an interesting theory on breaks.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid to go off-the-grid&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Trust me, I know it’s tempting to respond to a text or email right away. But dropping what you’re working on to respond immediately breaks up your workflow and squashes your productivity. Set aside a block (or two) of time each day for responding to emails. During the rest of the day, close your inbox and put your devices away.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Get your beauty sleep&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I know this is a hard one - it’s difficult to fit work, the gym, grocery shopping, dinner, etc. into a single day, let alone finish by a reasonable hour. But I cannot emphasize enough how important a good night’s sleep is! Check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/09/18/scary-sleep-deprivation-effects_n_2807026.html&#34;&gt; this Huffington Post article &lt;/a&gt; if you’re not convinced! Try your best not to pack too many things into a single day. And once you finally get to bed, put away your phone and computer (and other devices) to make the most of your limited rest time.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope these tricks work as well for you as they do for us! And feel free to share your favorite tips and tricks with us. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can&#39;t Find Your Files? You&#39;re Not Alone!</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/blog/notalone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 10:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/blog/notalone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have you needed a document on your computer but couldn’t find it right away?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re very meticulous about filing your documents in folders, maybe you opened the Finder or Windows Explorer and navigated to the correct folder. If you haven’t accessed the document in awhile, perhaps you clicked into the wrong folder at first. Or searched through Dropbox before realizing it was on Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;fullsize&#34; src=&#34;https://meta.sc/images/blog/cluttered_desktop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cluttered Desktop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If filing documents isn’t quite your thing, perhaps you searched around for the file on your Desktop. Or used Spotlight to search for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you didn’t find it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to find your documents, but none of them are satisfactory. They are “good enough” in the sense that they usually get you to the document you’re looking for. But how long does it take? How long do you spend clicking in and out of different folders or trying different search terms?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 2015, but we’re still using filing cabinet technology to organize files on our computers. To find a document, you must remember exactly where you saved it, what you named it, or exact words or phrases it contains. I don’t care how good you are, there’s no way someone could remember this much information for thousands of files. And if you can, teach me your secret!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody has presented a solution to this problem. Cloud storage services (Google Drive, Dropbox, OneDrive) allow you to access your files from anywhere, which is awesome. But you’re still left with the same primitive tools to find the files you stored on these platforms (navigating through folders and keyword search). But hey, now you can struggle to find your files from anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, there is finally hope! We’re developing Meta, an application that allows you to access any file in seconds, whether it’s saved on your computer, Dropbox, Google Drive, or in your email inbox. And the best part is you don’t have to remember what you named it or where you saved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrigued? Sign up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meta.sc/index.html#footer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a chance to participate in our beta!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS X Engineer</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:20:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/osx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You write efficient, elegant, and testable Objective-C and Swift to a high standard, in a timely and scalable way. You’re familiar with CoreData, AFNetworking, File System Events, XPC Services, Background/Login Applications, Status Bar Items, Spotlight Integrations, Local and Remote Notifications, App Sandbox, and Accessibility requirements. Intimate familiarity with the latest design guidelines for OSX is highly desirable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Front End Engineer</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/frontend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:43:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/frontend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You write fast, beautiful JavaScript to create simple and powerful user experiences. You translate visual designs into fully working web pages, and edit the HTML, CSS, and Javascript for existing page templates. You build and work with high-performance, reusable code for UI components and your work is always modular and scaleable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back End Engineer</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:43:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/backend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You implement robust and scalable systems in distributed environments and enjoy finding simple solutions to complex problems. You have the ability to convert high level design goals into clear and specific implementation plans. You care deeply about the performance of the systems that you build.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Engineer</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:44:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know search algorithms and have applied them in a commercial setting. You can dive into elaborate datasets and architect the algorithms behind modern search. You are excited to use your mathematical and algorithmic background to help us fix file management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Engineer</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are excited by the underlying structure and patterns hidden within complex datasets. You discover valuable metrics and insights from low level user interaction data. You transform abstract ideas into scalable production systems. You have experience leveraging user data to increase the quality of search engines using modern information retrieval techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack of All Trades</title>
      <link>https://meta.sc/careers/all/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:44:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meta.sc/careers/all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may not see the perfect fit in our existing job descriptions, but you love our concept and want to be involved. You are excited about revolutionizing the way people interact with their files. Meta offers challenges in user experience design, marketing, consumer behavior, and nearly every area of software engineering. If you think you would be a good fit, we can’t wait to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>